

Associate Engineering Manager

(±351) 93 502 44 10 • andygoncalves.com in andygoncalves seekandystroy



General

Traits An enthusiastic and straightforward team player, I love to learn and hear about different points of view. A true believer in honest feedback and nurturing relationships.

Interests Leadership and management. Agile. Distributed systems and cloud computing.

Experience Architecture and implementation of the backend of cloud applications. Team leading. Implementation of all the stack levels of web applications. Some experience in functional analysis and design of web and mobile applications. Master thesis in cloud computing.

Life Biker, keyboard enthusiast, thai/kick boxer.

Professional Experience

2020-now Talkdesk, (recent), Associate Engineering Manager, Cloud-based call center solution. Managing one of the core teams of the product.

People management and delivery.

2016–2020 Talkdesk, (4 years), Software Engineer, Cloud-based call center solution.

Developing, scrum mastering, and team leading.

Designing and developing the new core systems of the product, responsible for routing calls and other interactions. Maintaining the legacy call routing systems.

2013–2016 Safira/KPMG, (2 years, 5 months), Software Developer, IT for financial services. Full stack development of web applications, mobile web applications, and middlewares, for banks and insurance companies, using IBM technologies.

Education

2011–2013 Masters in Computer Science Engineering, Nova University, Lisbon, 17/20. 2 years MSc (Eng), focus on distributed systems. Thesis in cloud computing, grade of 18/20.

2012 **Teaching assistant**, Nova University, Lisbon, Introduction to Computers and Programming.

2008–2011 Diploma in Computer Science Engineering, Nova University, Lisbon, 15/20. 3 years BSc (Eng).

Technical Skills

General OO/functional programming, TDD, SOA and Microservices, event-driven architectures

Languages Ruby, Elixir (main ones). Java, Javascript, HTML5

DBs MongoDB, PostgreSQL, SQL Server

Tools Git, SVN, Unix/Linux usage, LATEX

Misc. Docker, Twilio, Heroku, IBM BPM, IIB/WMB

Last updated: 2020-03-10